## **JAGAN REDDY YERUVA**

jaganreddyyeruva@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Project Portfolio | +1 (206)5389188 | Seattle, WA-98109

# **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Certified Associate Project Manager (*CAPM*®) and experienced Business Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the logistics and international freight-forwarding industry. Led data-driven initiatives exceeding corporate objectives and made sound decisions that positively impacted both the revenue and increased clientele.

## **EDUCATION**

**University of Washington - Foster School of Business, Seattle** 

Master of Science in Information systems - "MSIS Top 10% Student Merit"

Osmania University, Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering

*Mar 2022 - June 2023* GPA : 3.9/4.0

Aug 2015 - Jun 2019

GPA: 3.55/4.0

# **SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS**

**Credentials:** Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM®)

(Cert. #3399316) - PMI (2023),

Certified Scrum Master (CSM®) from ScrumAlliance

(Cert. #1721652) - ScrumAlliance (2023),

Certified Associate Data Analyst Certificate

(Cert. #DAA0017056639746) - DataCamp (2022),

**Tech Skills:** Agile (Scrum) & Waterfall methodologies, SQL, Python, Business Intelligence tools (Tableau, PowerBI), Data Analysis, Microsoft Office tools (Excel [VBA, Pivot Tables], PowerPoint, Word, Outlook), JIRA, MS Project.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Airsea Forwarders India Pvt Ltd, Chennai

(South India's leading international logistics agents - Transportation, Logistics, Supply Chain, and Storage)

# Associate Project Coordinator

Aug 2020 – Jan 2022

- Coordinated with the project management team for over 100+ international freight forwarding shipments for high-profile clients including Samsung, Lenovo, and Dell India.
- Planned and executed shipment scope, cost estimation, resource procurement (shipping liners), and schedule development, resulting in an on-time and efficient delivery rate of over 90%.
- Exhibited interpersonal skills through effective communication and collaboration for better *Client and Vendor Management* with the executive team, resulting in a customer retention rate of over 97%.
- Proactively used *Business Strategy & Problem-solving* skills to manage project cost and schedule changes and effectively identified and resolved project risks and issues, resulting in a 25% reduction in project escalations.
- Demonstrated *Strong Attention to Detail* by defining KPIs such as average freight cost per tonne shipped, average margin, and quote conversion ratio resulting in an increase in customer satisfaction and loyalty.

## **Business Analyst**

June 2019 – Aug 2020

- Exhibited *Data and Business Analysis* key performance metrics such as shipment processing times, collaborated with 40+ stakeholders to understand pain points and opportunities for digitization, resulting in the company-seconded decision to implement an ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) system.
- Demonstrated strong Conflict resolution and Negotiation abilities by effectively communicating the mutual benefits of the ERP system to the vendor, resulting in successful on-time delivery and 25% within the project budget.
- Spearheaded the implementation of the ERP system, resulting in *successful deployment*, with 30min daily time saving per employee and overall better operational transparency and streamlined processes.
- Facilitated a successful employee training program, resulting in high user adoption, a 30% reduction in data entry errors, leading to better collaboration between teams and improved decision-making for management.

#### ACADEMIC PROJECTS

(Explore my other projects from my 'Project Portfolio' link)

<u>IT Product Design & Prototype Development</u> - *Links:* (<u>Prototype</u> | <u>Video Demo</u> | <u>Business Model Report</u>)

**May 2023** 

Skills involved: Managing Projects through human-centred design, Data Driven Product Decisions.

<u>'BlossoMum'</u> - app to help pregnant families throughout their journey by providing access to adequate resources like pregnancy tracker, baby health tracker, appointment scheduler, mood tracker, and a community platform using Agile.

- **User-Centered Design**: Conducted user interviews with 50+ respondents, primarily aged 27-36, to inform the development of the BlossoMum app, ensuring the design was tailored to meet user needs.
- **Data-Driven Development**: Analyzed feedback from 23 active resource users and 15 non-users to guide the app's development. Conducted usability tests with multiple users, leading to iterative improvements based on user feedback.

# <u>Video Game Sales - Descriptive and Diagnostic Analyses</u> - *Links:* (<u>Analysis Report</u>)

**June 2022** 

Skills involved: SQL, Python, Excel, Tableau

- Performed descriptive and diagnostic analyses to determine the global trend in video game console sales.
- Concluded that the paradigm shift in gaming industry was caused by rise of mobile gaming and introduction of 'Freemium' model games (free to play but require money to unlock certain features); mobile game market took over 51% of global gaming revenue in 2020 while PC games and console games evenly split the rest.

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Indigo Airlines (India's largest Commercial Airline)

Cadet Trainee Commercial Pilot Program | Apprenticeship